Ahmed Imtiaz

Network/System Engineer

ADDRESS: Gulshan Ravi, Lahore, Pakistan

CONTACT NO: +92 307 046 5698

EMAIL: writetoahmedimtiaz@gmail.com

LINKEDIN: Ahmed Imtiaz

ABOUT ME

A confident and reliable IT professional with 3+ years of experience of working as a technical support engineer and resolving any support issues that are raised to the service desk. Possessing professional training & certifications from CISCO, Microsoft, VMware etc. and have proven track record in network/system support helping clients and colleagues resolve complex technical IT issues. An excellent communicator can relate well with people at all levels and has the flexibility of working well as part of a team and on my own.

SKILLS

- IT Support & Troubleshooting
- Network & system support
- Computer Hardware & Software
- Windows Server (AD DS, DCHP, DNS)
- O365 & exchange online administration
- Ample knowledge of web design (HTML5,CSS,BootStrap)

WORK EXPERIENCE

FUTURENOW TECHNOLOGIES (PVT) LIMITED

System and Network Engineer

Jan 2022 - Present

- Providing L1/L2 support either face-to-face or remotely using remote tools such as Any desk,
 TeamViewer
- Use Active Directory and Exchange Management Console for managing users, groups, and computers.
- Setting up new user's AD & Email accounts & deal with password/login issues
- Service desk ticket management (Assign, follow up, resolution & close)
- Identifying, diagnosing and rectifying any issues in computer hardware, software, services and applications
- Continuous network & infrastructure monitoring using SolarWinds and PRTG
- Providing step-by-step technical help, both verbal & written, including procedural documents
- Support in day-to-day data center operations

Dunya News

Systems Support Engineer

Apr 2021 - Dec 2021

- Installing and configuring computer hardware, software, systems, printers and scanners
- Providing technical support to all users across the business.
- Setting up new user's AD & Email accounts & deal with password/login issues



Responding and resolving the support requests and service tickets in a timely manner

Lahore Logistics Pvt Ltd

IT Support Engineer

Mar 2019 - Feb 2021

- Troubleshoot and resolve hardware and software problems on desktops, laptops and other various computing equipment and devices
- Troubleshooting basic system and network problems and diagnosing, solving hardware or software faults
- Reimage laptops and desktops as needed following company policy
- Providing technical support to all the users across the business
- Providing step-by-step technical help, both verbal & written, including procedural documents

Trainings & CERTIFICATIONS

- Cisco Certified Network Associate (CCNA)
- Microsoft Certified: Azure Fundamentals
- Microsoft Certified: Azure Administrator Associate
- Microsoft Certified Solutions Associate (MCSA) Training

EDUCATION

BS Software Engineering – Lahore Leads University 2018

CHARACTERISTICS

- Strong will power and desire to succeed.
- Adaptable to changing working environment.
- Confident fast learner and dedicate in the performance of my duties & responsibilities with outstanding manners, discipline and sincerity.

LANGUAGES

ENGLISH: Good Speaking, Reading, Writing and Understanding **URDU:** Excellent Speaking, Reading, Writing and Understanding

REFERANCE

Will be furnished upon request.